# **Elizabeth Hedges**

elizabethjanehedges@gmail.com | LinkedIn

### **Skills**

#### **Professional skills**

Communication
Media
Content creation
Project Management
Leadership

## **Technical skills**

SEO

Content Relationship Management (CRM) Microsoft Office Suite Social Media Email Management

#### **Certificates**

#### **Google Ads**

LinkedIn 2024

## Remarketing Strategies with Google Ads and Analytics

LinkedIn 2024

## **Management Essentials**

LinkedIn 2024

## Project Communications Management

Udemy *2024* 

### **Adobe InDesign Essentials**

City Desktop Training 2022

### **Career Summary**

Five years' experienced communications professional in the private and public sectors. I am currently a Communications Advisor for the NSW Department of Climate Change, Energy, the Environment and Water. I am relocating from Australia to the United Kingdom this September. I am under the Youth Mobility Scheme visa and do not require work sponsorship.

#### **Relevant Work Experience**

#### **NSW Government**

## **Communications Advisor, NSW Office of Climate Change (Contract)**

Jan 2024 - present

- Leading a team of 7 members and effectively prioritising client requests and delegating tasks to ensure efficient workflow.
- Overseeing a Jira workload board comprising more than 400 project items, ensuring accurate tracking and timely completion of tasks.
- Crafting press releases to effectively communicate brand messaging.
- Authoring over six reactive media releases per week for the Minister for the Environment, Penny Sharpe.

## Communications and Engagement Advisor, NSW Premier's Department

Nov 2022 - Dec 2023

- Developed and distributed 123 communication messages to state departments on behalf of the NSW Premier and Secretaries.
- Oversaw internal intranet and ensure updates, alignment with brand and web content accessibility guidelines.
- Partnered with key stakeholders to provide strategic communication advice and recommendations.
- Managed and curated content across various social platforms, including overseeing a LinkedIn portfolio with 39,000 followers.

## Media and Communications Project Support Officer, NSW Biodiversity Conservation Trust (BCT)

Sep 2021 - Nov 2022

- Managed media relations for former Environmental Minister James
   Griffin and BCT publicity opportunities in traditional media.
- Created digital content for social media channels and directly contributed to quantifiable growth, including a 72% increase in Facebook presence and placing fifth on 'Pages to Watch'.
- Administered the BCT external communication lists on Salesforce CRM, ensuring that the data was relevant.
- Designed BCT quarterly newsletter, Understory and twelve yearly regional newsletters.

#### **Education**

## Bachelor of International Relations and Arts

Major English Minor Sustainable Development Australian National Unive

Australian National University (ANU)

2017 - 2020

#### Languages

### **English**

Fluent

### **Tagalog**

Conversational

#### **Leadership Experience**

# Acting Communications Director, Young Australians in International Affairs March 2024 - May 2024

- Managed a team of 4 Communication Officers, collaborating closely with key executive leadership to align strategies and objectives.
- Drafted and scheduled social media content calendar, comprising up to 10 posts a week across 4 channels.
- Maintained website, ensuring adherence to website accessibility guidelines and seamless user experience.

## **Content Creator, Difficult Women Book Club Sydney**

Feb 2024 - present

- Crafting weekly videos upholding brand standards through close collaboration with the founder.
- Rapidly grew following and engagement to over 4,000 followers and 31,000 likes.
- Managed complete video creation lifecycle from concept to posting, including creative development, scripting, and performance analysis.

#### Content Creator, TikTok

May 2023 - Present

- Owner of two popular TikTok accounts dedicated to popular cultural analysis and book reviews.
- Amassed 1.7 million likes and 10 million views through topical content.
- Adept at developing creative concepts, and leveraging TikTok's video editing tools to produce viral and shareable content.

# Secretariat, Young Professionals Network (YPN), NSW Premier's Department May 2023 - Nov 2023

- Coordinated administrative operations and logistics to streamline communication, planning, and execution initiatives.
- Facilitated educational seminars, including 'Introduction to Al' to upskill colleagues and promote knowledge sharing.
- Oversaw internal events such as weekly donation drives and other community outreach efforts.

## **Editorial Intern, Offspring Magazine**

May 2020 - Oct 2020

- Guided under Chief Executive Officer, Kate Durack, gaining valuable leadership insights and industry exposure.
- Crafted and published high-quality journalistic pieces.
- Spearheaded social media content creation, drafting and publishing weekly posts across Instagram and Facebook.

References provided upon request